Let's try to count from the sun
Давай попробуем посчитать от солнца
Let's count Let's RTO Mercury Venus
Давай считай Давай РТО Меркурий Венера
and Mars is right or Earth
а Марс правильно или Земля
so then who else is there that has a big one like A
так потом кто там ещё у которого большая
probably Saturn that's
типа А наверное Сатурн так
right Jupiter that's right
правильно Юпитер так правильно
and then who is faton Neptune Neptune no Neptune
а потом кто фатон Нептун Нептун нет
after fan Neptune and then
Нептун после фан Нептун и потом
Pluto
Плутон
Hello Hello let's have a normal
Приветик Привет давай нормально
chat
пообщаемся
what am I from the city of Khmelnitsky And where are you from
о чём я из города Хмельницке А ты откуда
And I'm from the Urals the city of Yekaterinburg
будешь А я с Урала город Екатеринбург
Yekaterina my father
екатери у меня отец в Свердловский
was born in Sverdlovsk Well when was he still in Sverdlovsk
родился Ну когда он ещё в Свердловском
well it's the same city was
был ну это тот же самый город
born if anything How old are you
родилась если что Сколько тебе
35 Yes that means you were born in
лет 35 Да значит родилась ещё в
Sverdlovsk Yes I understand what you're talking about
Свердловске Да понял о чём общаешься
baby Yes just like that at least about something it would be
малышка Да просто так хоть о чём кто-то
interesting If you removed
из было бы интересно Если бы ты убрал
all this I
всю Вот эту вот всякую символику
can do all this symbolism there Let's I'm ready to remove the
там могу сделать Давай я готов убрать
symbols and everything there if you tidy up a little
символику и всякое там если ты немножко
and at least a little bit you
навед порядок и хоть чу чучуть
will be pretty and that is like I'm ugly yes
будешь а то есть типа я страшная да я
I didn't say that but as
такого я такого не говорил но как бы
if  does my symbolism hurt you I'll
если тебе больно от моей символики Я
tell you honestly it hurts me from yours Well,
честно скажу мне больно от твоей Ну ну
he's alone So you yourself said something like
он один Так ты сам сказал типа то что
let's do it without politics I'm saying I'm
давай без политики я и говорю убираю я
removing it I did
флаг Украины моя вышиванка почему потому
n't say no politics I said let's have a normal conversation And why are you like that let's have a normal conversation look do you have someone in the war from your relatives no but from your acquaintances And there is someone who died And why don't you like the
Я не знаю как это объяснить Попробуй
Ukrainian flag my embroidered shirt
триггерит ну поставь российский флаг Ну
why because it's ...
же специально вышла с этим флагом да Для
where did I get this sweater
вообще знаешь откуда мне эта кофта
from? a because I love space and
откуда а потому что я люблю космос и у
I can do it,
меня это получается
it's super, about
это супер насчёт
this Gagarin, in short, well I get it, you love
этого Гагарина короче ну понял ты любишь
braids. Super Cool. I like girls
кос Супер Классно я Мне нравятся девушки
who love space. How many planets are there in the
которые любят Космос Сколько планет в
solar system
солнечной системе
and when did they stop considering Pluto a
а Плутон когда его перестали считать за
planet? In what year first? Well, how many
планету В каком году сначала Ну сколько
with or without Pluto? How many? I don't remember? Come on, well,
с плутоном или без сколько
we're space lovers. Come on. No,
А я не помню давай ну мы ж любители
I don't remember. Let's try to
Давай это Нет я не помню Давай попробуем
count from the sun. Let's count. Come on, that's enough.
посчитать от солнца Давай считай Давай
Mercury
Меркурий
Venus Mars is right or Earth,
Венера Марс правильно или Земля
so then who else is there that has a big one, like
так потом кто там ещё у которого большая
probably Saturn, that's
типа наверное Сатурн так
right. Jupiter is right,
правильно Юпитер так правильно
so then who's a fan of Neptune. Neptune is not Neptune,
а потом кто фан Нептун Нептун нет Нептун
then
после
and then
и потом
Pluto. In short, just Pluto, but you're
Плутон короче да просто Плутон но ты
great, you know that Pluto is
молодец ты знаешь что Плутон уже вроде
no longer considered a planet, but how much did it turn out to be?
как не считает планетой да то сколько
Let's count without Pluto,
получилось Давай посчитаем без Плутона
how many? Didn't you count or something? Duma.
сколько А ты что не считал что ли Дума
You were supposed to count. Come on, I didn't
Так ты же должна была считать Давай я не
count. Let's do it again. Okay, nine, nine without
считала Давай ещ Ладно девять девять без
Pluto,
Плутона
nine, you can name them in order again.
девять можешь ещё раз по порядку их
Why Understand Well, in short, let's
назвать Зачем Поня Ну короче давай
record what we got like this
зафиксируем что у нас получилось так
Mercury and you'll be filming me, but
Меркурий ве ты меня будешь снимать да
like no I want to record it for myself like this
типа не Я себе хочу зафиксировать так
then there was Mars then there was
потом был Марс потом
this Earth then Saturn then Jupiter
была это Земля потом Сатурн потом Юпитер
Phaeton Neptune Pluto Yes, that's great Well,
фаетон Нептун Плутон Да вот так супер Ну
you know about space
с космосом ты шаришь
Handsome And in what year did Gagarin fly into
Красава А в каком году Гагарин полетел в
space Oh, I don't remember that Well, the first
космос Ой это я не помню Да ну первый
person wait p Well, you're a
человек подожди п Ну ты любительница
space lover In what year did Gagarin fly into
космоса В каком году Гагарин полетел в
space Well, I'm not like that I'm just
космос Ну я же типа не этот я просто
like well a lover and not like that
типа ну любитель а не то что типа этот
some facts to remember I understand okay if you
какие-то факты помнить понял ладно если
want Gagarin flew into space in
хочешь Гагарин полетел в космос в 1981
1981 Just the year of my birth What is
году Как раз год мо рожде Что такое
singularity there or now
сингулярность там или сейчас сечас
now about singularity reception The thing is that I I was
сейчас про сингулярность приём Дело в
born in the year Gagarin
том что я Я родился в год когда Гагарин
flew into space That's why I remember 198
полетел в космос Я поэтому и помню 198
first Here you can tell about
первы Вот про можешь сказать про
singularity Well, tell me about
сингулярность А ну расскажи про
singularity
сингулярность
well when, for example, a star burns
хорошо когда допустим у звезды сгорает
this fuel Well, like there is hydrogen  in short
это топливо Ну типа там водород короче
there usually Well, like a star usually has
там обычно Ну типа у звезды обычно
hydrogen
водород
There's just Hey you do
Там просто Эй ты меня по-любому это да
n't give me any idea this is not Tell me about singularity I don't
не Расскажи мне про сингулярность Я не
know what singularity is honestly So
знаю что такое сингулярность честно Так
google it better I'm googling it now Tell
загугли лучше я сейчас гуглю Расскажи
me in your own
мне своими
words In short
словами Короче
when it
когда
gets heavier inside than outside that's
а внутри становится тяжелее чем снаружи
where it's heavier inside than outside and by the way I did
где внутри тяжелее чем снаружи и причём
n't understand what
не понял то что такое
singularity is Are you kidding
сингулярность Ты что издеваешься надо
me or what am I honestly Look I know about
мной или что я честно Смотри Я знаю про
Gagarin I know about the planets I learned this at
Гагарина Я знаю про планеты Это я учил в
school yes but I didn't learn What is
школе да но я не учил Что такое
singularity it's something modern
сингулярность это что-то современное
honestly I'm
честно мне
interested so google it I'll read this
интересно так загугли почитаю этого
Stephen Hawking Stephen
стина Хокинга Стивена
Hawking And who is Stephen Hawking Well, that's the
Хокинга А кто такой Стивен Хокинг Ну это
Polish guy who rode around in a wheelchair and
который полиш на этом ездил на коляске и
said this by the way he's the one Have you
говорил это он кстати вообще Вот ты
read Stephen Hawking
читала Стивена Хокинга
Of course it's
Конечно
cool And what work by Stephen Hawking have
прикольно А какую работу Стивена Хокинга
you read He only has one book
Ты читала у него только одна есть книга
that's like popular like well
которая типа популярна типа ну
how can I say it physics astrophysicist like
э как это сказать физику астрофизик типа
into the popular masses like in
в популярную массу типа
simple language more or less like here
это простым языком более-менее типа вот
he has  she's alone well what was it called
у него одна она ну как как она назвалась
you read it I just want to
Ты же её читала Я просто хочу тоже
read it too I don't remember And what
почитать я не помню А что нарисовано
was drawn on the cover at
было на обложке хотя
least I read from my phone and from my phone well
бы я читала с телефона а с телефона ну
damn I can't find it I'm interested yes so
блин я найти мне интересно да так
google it I understand I understand it's interesting Listen well well
загугли понял Понял интересно Слушай а
you like this space specialist
вот ну ты как этот специалист по космосу
uh What is the first koche I'm not a
ээ Что такое первоя коче я не специалист
space specialist I'm just an amateur amateur Yes
по космосу Я просто любитель любитель Да
what is it I also heard several
что такое вот я слышал тоже несколько
amateurs talking saying that
любителей разговаривали говорили что
there is an aphelion perihelion what is it
есть там афелий перигелий что это
helium - this is in short the closest
такое гели - это короче самая ближа
point well when some
точка ну когда там какой-то
object comes like well to
объект приходит типа ну чтобы его
see it Well helium relative to something there are
видеть Ну гели относительно чего то есть
heliums I don't know I just heard
гели есть бы я не знаю я просто слышал
such words yes So I'm telling you helium
такие слова да Так я тебе и говорю гели
relative to something let's say the Moon
относительно чего то есть допустим Луны
you
ты это
see it yourself Well when it The Moon is big
видишь сам Ну когда она Луна большая
just Well
просто
like the closest point like this is
типа наиболее близкая точка типа это вот
clear And which one is the most By the way You should
понятно А какой самый Вот кстати Это ты
know what is the most famous
должна знать какой самый известный
satellite of Venus Venus has no satellites
спутник Венеры у Венеры нет спутников
there are no two satellites yes And one of them is the
есть нет два спутника да И один из них
most famous they are just small
самый известный они просто маленькие
no this is
нету это
known Apollo
зна Аполлон
wait you were just on the toilet  was
подожди ты только что на унитазе была
yes
да
cool And what else are you interested in on the space
прикольно А что ещё тебя по космической
theme I'm
теме интересует мне ж
interested I don't know at least what and where did
интересно Не знаю хоть что а откуда у
you get this who gave you this T-
тебя вот это кто тебе подарил эту
shirt girls gave it to me
футболку это мне девочки подарили
girls and girls for my birthday Yes
девочки а девочки на день рождения Да
they know you
они знают ти
I girls know that you are into
я девочки знают что ты увлекаешься
space and they gave it to you Yes I
космосом и они тебе подарили
understand And do you know what else is
Да понял А знаешь что есть такое ещё
perihelion there is apogee
перигелий есть апогей
apogee
апогей
aphelion
афелий
maybe And what is
может А что такое
apogee it is the most deviated that is
апогей это наиболее отклонён то есть
like a distant point This is aphelion from
типа отдалённая точка Это афелий от
observation not in orbit there are
наблюдения не на орбите есть
helium aphelion No I'll look now Come on
гели афелий Нет я сейчас посмотрю Давай
let's
давай
google
загуглю
aphelion And it is also apogee Yes it is a synonym
афелий А и он же апогей Да это синоним
Aphelion and apogee it is one and the same also you see
Афелия и апогея это одно и тоже также
my
вишь мо
right
право
yes cool So what else do you know I do
да прикольно Так что ты ещё
n't know Ask I
знаешь не знаю Спрашивай
understand But do you know what is there a
понял А вот знаешь что такое есть
telescope like
телескоп типа
this in words in words like apogee and peri
это в словах в словах типа апогей и пере
helium there is a root helium from the word sun
гелий есть корень гелий от слово солнце
Helius Helius is right well done Listen
Гелиус Гелиус правильно молодец Слушай
you are so super you are not completely stupid more precisely
ты так супер ты не совсем глупая точнее
not stupid at all Well or not really well in
совсем не глупая Ну или не совсем ну
short something like that what else
короче что-то в этом роде что тебя ещё
interests you about
интересует по
space I don't know Ask
космосу не знаю Спрашивай
I'm just not strong in space I don't
Я просто не силён в космосе мне я не
understand what could be there at all
понимаю что там вообще может
Well what is the closest star
быть Ну какая самая ближе близкая звезда
to the earth I do
к земле
n't know to be honest But
а не знаю если честно А
think about it I remember but I teach Ed at school
подумать я помню но я Эду в школе учат
every child knows this star the
каждый ребёнок знает эту звезду самая
closest star No the closest star
ближняя звезда Нет самая близкая звезда
to the
к
earth the sun the sun
земле солнце солнце
[laughter]
[смех]
yes and besides the sun What star is the
да а кроме солнца Какая звезда самая
closest to the Sun Well to the
ближе к Солнцу Ну к
earth that's why I thought about it I don't know
земле вот Я поэтому и задумалась не знаю
no And in which galaxy is it located it is
не А в какой она галактике находится она
in the constellation Centaurus it is located In which
в созвездии Центавра находится В какой
galaxy is it located I don't know The
галактике она находится не знаю
Milky Way galaxy for
Галактика Млечный
sure Do you know And in short there is a star like that
точно А ты знаешь А есть короче звезда
it is in
такая она в
this constellation
этом созвездие
Orion what is it I
Ориона как она
forgot the
я забыла
name Come on
название Давай
Al no it will go out
Аль нет погаснет
soon don't
скоро не
hang up my astrophysics don't hang up
Зависай моя астрофизика не Зависай
please In short it It
пожалуйста Короче
should soon like
она Она скоро должна типа
this can you google
это можешь загуглить
what is it called
как она называется
damn you with money or something I will take your
блин те баблом что ли я Я поверю на
word that there is such a star yes what is it
слово что есть такая Звезда да как она
called I will not calm down yet  I don't
называется я не успокоюсь пока не
remember
вспомню
in the constellation of Arion Let me google it so you
в созвездие ариона Давай загуглю чтоб ты
calm down And then you drive now Yes, so it
успокоилась А то ты сейчас водишь Да так
turns out that it's on that
получается с той
side Rigel Begei Bellatrix
стороны ригель бегей беллатрикс
Bilge You just got it
бильге ты аж прям получила
astronomically that's the only thing you
астрономически это единственное что ты
got
получала
yes yes no I understand So what should happen to this Begei Well,
да да нет понял Так и что с этой бегей
like it's
должно случиться Ну типа она как будто
supposed to explode soon Well,
бы должна в ближайшее время взорваться
like a supernova
Ну как сверхновая
Or maybe it's already exploded Well,
А может быть она уже взорвалась Ну
consider it there And you can put the phone
считай там А ты можешь поставить телефон
you jerk your hands just put it in
ты дёргаешь руками просто постави его
front of
перед
you Oh so how are you better or you're
собой О так как ты лучше а то тебя
shaking as if you're going into orbit
Трусит как будто ты на Орбиту выходишь
Yes, I'm just afraid you'll take a picture of me there and
Да я просто боюсь ты меня сфоткаешь там
send me somewhere And if I wanted to I would have
куда-нибудь отправишь А я если бы хотел
taken a picture a long time ago
уже давно бы сфоткал
What else is interesting about space can you
что ещё по космосу интересного можешь
tell me What is the rotation period of the comet
рассказать какой Период вращения кометы
Galeia What the hell is it next time
Галея Ты что блин она в следующий раз
only
только
in I don't remember Well, in short, it's
через я не помню ну короче она
somewhere We, in short, no, we won't wait for this But it
где-то мы короче не это не дождёмся Зато
was How approximately is it how
была Сколько приблизительно она сколько
approximately is it once in How many
приблизительно она раз в Сколько
years but it was somewhere in the eighties for the
лет но она была где-то в восьмидесятом
first
году первый
time in  next time it
раз в следующий раз она
will be well 100 something Years shorter Comet
будет ну 100 с чем-то Лет короче комета
Galey 76 years
Галея 76 лет Период
Rotation period And why is it called Comet
вращения А почему она называется комета
Galey and not Comet Geli Comet Hale
Галея а не комета гели Комета Хейла
Bopp Hale Bopp was in the early
Боппа Хейла Боппа было в начало
2000s no in the early 2000s
двухтысячных нет в начале дся
and it was a comet hanging yes We remember
бы и это была комета висела да Мы помним
We were in high school once 2000 years oh
Мы в старших классах были раз 2000 лет о
this comet really was which I
эта комета реально была которую я
saw
увидела
and and in short well I was probably years old then
и и короче ну у меня было тогда лет
I just like it was so it
наверно Я просто типа это так это
impressed And after that I started
впечатлила И после этого я начала
to get carried away
увлекаться
like it's cool I have like a telescope
типа прикольно У меня есть типа телескоп
there well this It's like this
там
on me it's such an
вот ну это Это она так на меня это такое
impression phenomenon Yeah I still
впечатление вление Угу я до сих пор
remember damn and here it was In short it turns out
помню блин а тут была Короче получается
this
в этом
October it flew by yes there was such a
октябре она пролетала да там такая
hat
шляпа
Well all the same it can't compare with Tay with the
Ну всё равно она не сравнится с Тей с
comet that I saw Listen
той кометой которую видела Слушай а
can you show me You said you have a
можешь показать Ты говорила у тебя есть
telescope can you show me your telescope
телескоп можешь показать свой телескоп
bring it Yes
принеси Да
come on what is the diameter of your
давай сколько диаметр твоего
telescope 20 what Show me your
телескопа 20 че Покажи свой
telescope Well in short that's how you have it there what kind of
телескоп Ну короче вот так у тебя там
light pollution  there is a
такая это световое загрязнение какой там
telescope so that's what I'm talking about,
телескоп так вот я про то и говорю что
like
типа
you're stupidly looking at the illuminated city, in short, it's
это ты ту тупо на освещённый город
cool But by the way, why is the sun
Прикольно А вот кстати почему вот солнце
- It's Helios and helium is called yes
- Это Гелиос так и гелий называется да
But for some reason the comet was not named
Но почему-то комету назвали не комета
Helium's comet but
Гелия а комета
Galey's comet because Galileo discovered it Oh,
Галея потому что Галилей её открыл Ой
in short Who discovered it like Who
этот короче Кто открыл типа Кто
discovered it How do I know well Galileo
открыл Да откуда я знаю ну Галилео
Galilei And why was it not named
Галилей А почему назвали не комета
Galileo's comet but
Галилея а комета
Galey's comet I don't know I don't know yes yes Because
Галея не знаю не знаю да да Потому что
when Yes I know because yes Because when they
когда Да знаю потому да Потому что когда
wrote it down Well, there were no
записывали Ну раньше же не было
computers before and so on Yes Galileo
компьютеров и так дальше Да Галилео
Galilei sent the information to the
Галилей отправил информацию в
Astrophysical Society Yes and his
астрофизической общество Да и его
last name was written incorrectly they wrote
фамилию неправильно написали написали
Halley they made
галлей сделали комета
Halley's comet in short since
галлея короче с тех
then Are there rules among astronomers if
пор А есть среди астрономов правила если
an object is named it is not
объект назвали его уже не
renamed I do
переименовывают
n't know about such a thing,
о такое не
so a street can be renamed
знаю поэтому улицу могут переименовать
there Lenin for example there someone
там Ленина на там например кого-то
else but there is no longer a comet there an asteroid
другого а вот астероид там кометы уже
only because there I
нет только потому что там
realized what else interesting things you can tell about space
и понял что ещё интересного про космос
just like that Well, a
расскажешь просто ты вот так
lot  I know everything, then I'm weak
Ну много всего знаешь я то сла я нита
I don't know if you ask I
Я не знаю се спросишь
just understood I can't just take
просто понял я так не могу просто взять
and tell I
и рассказывать
understood In honor of which scientist the
понял В честь какой учёной названа
planet
планета
Venus was named not a scientist But in honor of
Венера не учёной А в честь
this some Greek goddess And to the goddess of
этой какой-то богини греческой А богине
what
чего
definitely not the goddess of Love Aphrodite was and
точно не богиня Любви Афродита была а
Venus Aphrodite was not
Венера Афродита не была
fierce
лю
and Venus was not in Greece at all but
та и Венера то вообще не в Греции была а
in
в
Rome I don't
Риме Я не
know I can tell what the
знаю я могу рассказать из чего стоят
clouds of Venus are made of damn What is the density of
облака Венеры блин Какая плотность у
wawawawa astronomical Give me
вававава астрономические Давай данные
encyclopedic data Tell me about the
энциклопедические Расскажи про облака
density of the clouds of Venus Do you really need to know this
плотность А тебе реально нужно это знать
Yes yes I don't think this is
Да да Мне кажется это вряд ли
necessary What is the density of the clouds of
надо Какова плотность облаков
Venus
Венеры
large more than And at least on Earth Well
большая больше чем А у Земли как минимум
what What is the atmospheric pressure on the
Ну какая Какое давление атмосферное на
surface of
поверхности
Venus I don't
Венеры не
know in numbers I really don't know but more
знаю в цифрах реально не знаю но больше
than on
чем на
Earth something doubtful to me will be
земле что-то сомнительно мне будет
now yes 95 atmospheres Yes
сейчас дасе 95 атмосфер Да
more better tell me about Mars what about
больше лучше скажи про Марс что про
Mars
Марс
Well what do you think I have such
Ну а ты что думаешь у меня прямо такие
encyclopedic knowledge not just
энциклопедические знания не не просто
just what's interesting Well you're
просто что интересно Ну ты же
into space you're there with a telescope
увлекаешься космосом ты там в телескоп
you watch Day and night you understand
смотришь Днями и ночами понимаешь
No I don't watch Day and night Why do you
Нет я не смотрю Днями и ночами А зачем
have it
он у тебя
Well when something interesting like
Ну когда что-нибудь интересное типа
then I watch And what's interesting there what are
тогда я смотрю А что там интересное что
you interesting I watched
ты интересное Смотрела последний
Jupiter last time when it came here where it
раз Юпитер когда сюда пришёл куда
came
пришёл
Yekaterinburg you came to nowhere I can't
Екатеринбург ты не куда пришёл Я не могу
understand adj so that it can be seen And like I understood
понять прил что бы видно А типа понял
just you say And what's written on the cup
просто ты говоришь А что на чашке
by the way the revolution that
написано кстати революция что
ours show me this I have a working No not by
наша покажи это у меня Рабочая Нет не по
And what was there a
А что там была
revolution there was a revolution yes in the years when there
революция революция была да годах когда
was a revolution Listen, did you ever have
была революция Слушай а ты когда-то у
some open let's
какое-то открывай
say friendship with some
ну скажем дружба с каким-то
astronaut damn it got
космонавтом блин
stuck develop a dream goddess Aphrodite
зависла разви сни богиня Афродита
at the end unscrews a bottle with her teeth It's
в конце е бутылку зубами откручивает Это
just
просто
crazy about space she talk No well
жесть о космосе она поговори Не ну
planets clearly
планеты чётко
name like squeak comment and drop y
называ лайк писка комент и скиньте й
joke all I know Hi
прикол всм знам Хай
subscribe to y Instagram I don't know what
подпишись на й Instagram Я не знаю для
it's for What else  tob there watch
чого це тоб Для чего ще тоб там дивитись
this and fie But for you it's one two
на оцей й фе Але для тебе це один два
or three clicks and you try me and I'll be there
або три клика а ты тримае мене и я буду
in me there are a bunch of fouls and in me there will be a
тиу в мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
cool naib Robbie but cool video letter on y
класный найб Роби но крут вдео пись на й
Instagram popk Andriy that's it
Instagram попк Андрий вот
come on I'm waiting for you
так давай я тебя чекаю